lookseewellington.co.nz 2018-12-22

# Privacy Policy » Connecting talent around the world with jobs in New Zealand

This privacy policy applies to Haines NZ Ltd. and all associated brands, including Workhere, LookSee, Round Peg, HainesAttract, and HainesLink. The privacy notice applies to personal and other information collected on these websites for all users and visitors.

###### Definitions

Haines NZ Ltd. (“our,” “we” or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, store, use and distribute information through our software, website, databases, documentation, and related services (together, the “Services”).

In this privacy statement, any reference to “Candidates” can refer to job seekers who have registered with us, applied for a job with us, or contacted us regarding job opportunities. Any reference to “Clients” can refer to anyone purchasing our Services, such as employers or advertisers. Candidates, Clients and users who otherwise use our Services are referred to generically in this Statement as “visitors”, "users" or "you.”

References to “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy are equivalent to “personal data” governed by European data protection legislation.

###### Consent

By providing your information to us and using the Services, you consent to the use of your Personal Information as described in this privacy policy. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, your Personal Information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent. We do not collect Personal Information for the purpose of sales of such information in a way that identifies the individual (i.e. we don’t sell customer lists). You may withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Information at any time. However, withdrawing consent may result in your inability to continue using some or all of our Services.

###### Data collection and purpose

When using our Services, we may require or ask you to provide certain personally identifiable information (these are referred to below as your “Personal Information”).

Our Services are designed to connect employers and candidates. To provide those services, we need your Personal Information.

The Personal Information that we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name and email address. Additionally, for clients we may also collect information about the company you represent. For candidates, we may collect information related to your job history and job search. If purchasing our Services, we may require you to provide financial and billing information, such as billing name and address, and credit card number (“Billing Information”).

For Candidates, we collect information for the purpose of presenting you to prospective employers or potential job opportunities. For Clients, we collect information for the purpose of providing you advertising, media and recruitment solutions. Providing us with this information can help us tailor our Services to you and make them more effective.

By providing us with your Personal Information, you give us permission to contact you about our Services. We may use your Personal Information to contact you with e-newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

Any personal information we hold will not be used by us for any purpose other than the one you provided it for, or disclosed to any other person in a form that will identify you except where you have consented to such disclosure, or where such use or disclosure is required or otherwise permitted by the New Zealand Privacy Act 1993, or otherwise required or permitted by law.

You have the right to access and to request correction of any of your personal information provided to us. If you would like to see the personal information relating to you that we have stored, or to request correction of such personal information, or if you have any concerns regarding your privacy, please email [privacy@hainesattract.co.nz](mailto:privacy@hainesattract.co.nz). We may require proof of your identity before being able to provide you with any personal information. See more details about your rights below.

###### Lawful Basis for Data Processing

We will only collect, store, and process your personal information where a lawful basis for such processing exists, which will typically fall under one of the following scenarios:

  1. You have given consent to the processing of your personal information for one or more specific purposes, for example by consenting to terms and conditions on our website, or application or registration forms, and consenting to the terms of this privacy policy;
  2. Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party;
  3. Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Haines NZ Ltd. as a Controller is subject;
  4. Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us as the Controller, or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of you which require protection of your personal information.

We may use your personal information for reasons not described in this Privacy Policy where permitted by law and the reason is compatible with the purpose for which we collected it.

###### Disclosures & Transfers

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside New Zealand and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to New Zealand and process it here.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

From time to time we may employ third parties as contractors to help us provide and/or improve the Services. These third parties may have limited access to Personal Information solely for the purpose of helping us to provide and/or improve the Services and they will be subject to contractual restrictions prohibiting them from using the information about our users for any other purpose. Such agents or third parties do not have any rights to use Personal Information beyond what is necessary to assist us.

We may also disclose your Personal Information with your consent.

###### Retention

We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, or until you delete or ask for your Information to be deleted.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

We may periodically ask you if we can continue to hold your information.

If you ask us to delete or remove your Personal Information we may not be able to provide our Services to you.

We may have to retain some information to comply with New Zealand or international legislation.

###### Your rights

New Zealand and International laws give you certain rights regarding your personal information. You may ask us to take the following actions in relation to your personal information that we hold:

  * Opt-out. Request to stop receiving or unsubscribe from direct marketing communications.
  * Access. Provide you with information about our processing of your personal information.
  * Correct. Update or correct inaccuracies in your personal information.
  * Delete. Delete your personal information.
  * Transfer. Transfer an electronic copy of your personal information to you or a third party of your choice.
  * Object. Object to our reliance on our legitimate interests as the basis of our processing of your personal information that impacts your rights.
  * Withdraw consent. Withdraw your consent for us to hold or use your Personal Information.

We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and process your request. Applicable law may require or permit us to decline your request. If we decline your request, we will tell you why, subject to legal restrictions.

If you would like to submit a complaint about our use of your personal information or response to your requests regarding your personal information, you may contact us at [privacy@hainesattract.co.nz](mailto:privacy@hainesattract.co.nz) or submit a complaint to the data protection regulator in your jurisdiction.

###### Automatic collection of information

We use site statistics to improve the information on this site and create relevant content. This information is viewable by site administrators and all information is used as non-personal.

This information includes: users' IP addresses, users' search terms, sections viewed on the site, links that are clicked on, date and time of site visits, previous visited site, users' operating systems, browsers used when accessing the site.

Google may also collect some or all of this information when javascript is turned on in your Internet browser. This is due to the site using a portion of the Google public index for its search functionality. Google’s use of such information is addressed in its Privacy Policy.

###### Cookies

Some of our websites, such as LookSee and Workhere, generate both persistent and temporary cookies (files that a website transfers to your computer).

Some cookies may collect personal information. You may decide to disclose by providing identifying information within the search terms you enter into the websites or when completing one of the website’s online forms.

The website generates temporary cookies to monitor site usage and to maintain site presentation for those who wish to use the website’s high contrast view.

If you prefer not to use cookies, you can still use our websites. To find out how to disable cookies, check the help instructions in your web browser.

###### Statistical Information

You can browse our websites without having to disclose any personal data. However, we may collect statistical information about your visit to help us analyse usage and improve our websites. This information includes, but is not limited to:

  * users' IP addresses and location
  * users' search terms
  * pages accessed on the website
  * links that are clicked on
  * date and time of visits
  * previous visits to the website
  * users' operating systems
  * browsers and devices used when accessing the website.

This information is viewable by our website Administrators and some Haines NZ Ltd. employees. It may also be shared with business partners such as employers, Immigration New Zealand or other government agencies.

This information may be used for statistical or research purposes and will not be published in a form that could reasonably be expected to identify you.

###### Remarketing

Our websites may utilise Remarketing with Google Analytics and Facebook to advertise online. It allows third-party vendors, including Google and Facebook, to show our advertisements on sites across the Internet. This is done by this site and third-party vendors, including Google and Facebook, using first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to this website.

###### Controller

Haines NZ Ltd. is the controller of your personal information for purposes of European data protection legislation. You can contact us at [privacy@hainesattract.co.nz](mailto:privacy@hainesattract.co.nz).

###### Contact Us

You can help by keeping us informed of any changes such as a change of email address or employment status. If you would like to access your information, if you have any questions, comments or suggestions or if you find any errors in our information about you, please contact us at [privacy@hainesattract.co.nz](mailto:privacy@hainesattract.co.nz) or 0800 170 019.

If you have a complaint concerning our compliance with applicable privacy laws, we will investigate your complaint and if it is justified, we will take appropriate measures.

Last Updated: 25 May 2018
